{"data":{"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","address":"330 Oakwood Blvd S","zipcode":"48217","owner":"Frances C Truant","licenseNumber":"035075","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","mostRecentLicenseDate":"4/26/2016","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":null,"reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","geom":"0101000020E6100000A46A0C515DC954C05843079C26254540","inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"44766","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","inspectionDate":"2019-01-04T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"140","pcount":"3","pfcount":"0","ccount":"1","criticalcount":"3","noncritical":"1","correctedcritical":"3","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"44766","inspectionDate":"1/4/2019","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"3-501.14","violationDescription":"(A)  Cooked POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be cooled:\r\n         (1)  Within 2 hours, from 135ºF to 70ºF; and (P) \r\n         (2)  Within 4 hours, from 70ºF to 41ºF or less (P)\r\n(B)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared from ingredients at ambient temperature shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41F or less. (P)\r\n(C)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  received in compliance with LAWS   allowing a temperature above 41ºF during shipment from the supplier shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41ºF or less. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Cooked food(s) cooled","subItem":"","problemDescription":"From 70 degrees f to 41 degrees F for more than 4 hours","subProblem":"","location":"COOLER","subLocation":"WALK-IN COOLER","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2019-01-04T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"inspectionid":"44766","inspectionDate":"1/4/2019","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"7-202.12","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIALS shall be:    \r\n(A) Used according to:      \r\n(1) LAW and this Code,   \r\n(2) Manufacturer's use directions included in labeling, and, for a pesticide, manufacturer's label instructions that state that use is allowed in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, (P)   \r\n(3) The conditions of certification, if certification is required, for use of the pest control materials, (P) and   \r\n(4) Additional conditions that may be established by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY; and\r\n(B) Applied so that:      \r\n(1) A HAZARD to EMPLOYEES or other PERSONS is not constituted, (P) and   \r\n(2) Contamination including toxic residues due to drip, drain, fog, splash or spray on FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES is prevented, and for a RESTRICTED USE PESTICIDE, this is achieved by: (P)      \r\n(a) Removing the items, (P)   \r\n(b) Covering the items with impermeable covers, (P) or   \r\n(c) Taking other appropriate preventive actions, (P) and   \r\n(d) Cleaning and SANITIZING EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS after the application. (P)  \r\n(C) A RESTRICTED USE PESTICIDE shall be applied only by an applicator certified as defined in 7 USC 136 Definitions, (e) Certified Applicator, of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, or a PERSON under the direct supervision of a certified applicator. (Pf)","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not used according to manufacturer's label instructions","subProblem":"","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"Pest Control Device","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2019-01-04T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Use according to manufacturer label directions."},{"inspectionid":"44766","inspectionDate":"1/4/2019","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"3-302.11","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD shall be protected from cross contamination by:  \r\n(1) Except as specified in (1)(c) below, separating raw animal FOODS during         storage, preparation, holding, and display from:\r\n(a) Raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD including other raw animal FOOD such as FISH for sushi or MOLLUSCAN SHELLFISH, or other raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD such as fruits and vegetables,(P) and\r\n(b) Cooked READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(c) Frozen, commercially processed and packaged raw animal FOOD may be          stored or displayed with or above frozen, commercially processed and           packaged, ready-to-eat food.\r\n(2) Except when combined as ingredients, separating types of raw animal FOODS    from each other such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, and POULTRY during storage,        preparation, holding, and display by:\r\n(a) Using separate EQUIPMENT for each type, (P) or\r\n(b) Arranging each type of FOOD in EQUIPMENT so that cross contamination of one type with another is prevented, (P) and\r\n(c) Preparing each type of FOOD at different times or in separate areas; (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Raw animal food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/next to","subProblem":"Ready-to-eat food(s)","location":"COOLER","subLocation":"WALK-IN COOLER","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2019-01-04T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store raw animal foods below and away from foods needing little or no further prep."},{"inspectionid":"44766","inspectionDate":"1/4/2019","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"2-402.11","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall wear hair restraints such as hats, hair coverings or nets, beard restraints, and clothing that covers body hair, that are designed and worn to effectively keep their hair from contacting exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; or unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE or SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Hair restraint","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not worn on head/hair","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Hair Restraints/Covering","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide hat or hair net."}]},{"inspectionid":"42820","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","inspectionDate":"2018-07-06T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"128","pcount":"1","pfcount":"1","ccount":"1","criticalcount":"2","noncritical":"1","correctedcritical":"2","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"42820","inspectionDate":"7/6/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"3-501.17","violationDescription":"(A)  READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared and held refrigerated for more than 24 hours in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT  shall be clearly marked at the time of preparation to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n(B)  A container of refrigerated, commercially prepared READY-TO-EAT POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be clearly marked, at the time the original container is opened in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n\r\nA date marking system that does not exceed 7 days, including date of preparation, or opening is to be used. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"In house prepared ready-to-eat potentially hazardous  food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Without date of consumption marking","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-07-06T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Establishment shall provide a clear date marking system."},{"inspectionid":"42820","inspectionDate":"7/6/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"8-201.12","violationDescription":"The plans and specifications for a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, including a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT specified under § 8-201.13, shall include, as required by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY based on the type of operation, type of FOOD preparation, and FOODS prepared, the following information to demonstrate conformance with Code provisions:\r\n(A) Intended menu;\r\n(B) Anticipated volume of FOOD to be stored, prepared, and sold or served;\r\n(C) Proposed layout, mechanical schematics, construction materials, and finish schedules;\r\n(D) Proposed EQUIPMENT types, manufacturers, model numbers, locations, dimensions, performance capacities, and installation specifications;\r\n(E) Evidence that standard procedures that ensure compliance with the requirements of this Code are developed or are being developed; and\r\n(F) Other information that may be required by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY for the proper review of the proposed construction, conversion or modification, and procedures for operating a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Plan(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Do not include","subProblem":"Standard procedures that comply with rule","location":"RESTAURANT","subLocation":"Above the","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Plans shall include all items listed above."},{"inspectionid":"42820","inspectionDate":"7/6/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"3-501.18","violationDescription":"A FOOD specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A) or (B) shall be discarded if it:  \r\n    (1) Exceeds the temperature and time combination specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A),              except time that the product is frozen; (P)\r\n    (2) Is in a container or PACKAGE that does not bear a date or day; (P) or\r\n    (3) Is appropriately marked with a date or day that exceeds a temperature and              time combination as specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A). (P)  \r\n\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Ready to eat, potentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly date marked","subProblem":"","location":"Refrigerator","subLocation":"Above the","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-07-06T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Establishment shall provide a clear date marking system."}]},{"inspectionid":"39962","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","inspectionDate":"2017-09-15T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"128","pcount":"0","pfcount":"2","ccount":"2","criticalcount":"2","noncritical":"2","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"39962","inspectionDate":"9/15/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"3-501.17","violationDescription":"(A)  READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared and held refrigerated for more than 24 hours in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT  shall be clearly marked at the time of preparation to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n(B)  A container of refrigerated, commercially prepared READY-TO-EAT POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be clearly marked, at the time the original container is opened in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n\r\nA date marking system that does not exceed 7 days, including date of preparation, or opening is to be used. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"In house prepared ready-to-eat potentially hazardous  food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Without date of consumption marking","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Establishment shall provide a clear date marking system."},{"inspectionid":"39962","inspectionDate":"9/15/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"3-501.15","violationDescription":"(A) Cooling shall be accomplished in accordance with the time and temperature criteria specified under § 3-501.14 by using one or more of the following methods based on the type of FOOD being cooled:  \r\n   (1) Placing the FOOD in shallow pans; (Pf)\r\n   (2) Separating the FOOD into smaller or thinner portions; (Pf)\r\n   (3) Using rapid cooling EQUIPMENT; (Pf)\r\n   (4) Stirring the FOOD in a container placed in an ice water bath; (Pf)\r\n   (5) Using containers that facilitate heat transfer; (Pf)\r\n   (6) Adding ice as an ingredient; (Pf) or\r\n   (7) Other effective methods. (Pf)  \r\n(B) When placed in cooling or cold holding EQUIPMENT, FOOD containers in which FOOD is being cooled shall be:  \r\n   (1) Arranged in the EQUIPMENT to provide maximum heat transfer through the       container walls; and\r\n   (2) Loosely covered, or uncovered if protected from overhead contamination as          specified under Subparagraph 3-305.11(A)(2), during the cooling period to facilitate    heat transfer from the surface of the FOOD.","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Food item(s) cooled","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly","subProblem":"In large container","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Remove and replace to be in compliance with law."},{"inspectionid":"39962","inspectionDate":"9/15/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"6-301.14","violationDescription":"A sign or poster that notifies FOOD EMPLOYEES to wash their hands shall be provided at all HANDWASHING SINKS used by FOOD EMPLOYEES and shall be clearly visible to FOOD EMPLOYEES.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Handwashing signage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide."},{"inspectionid":"39962","inspectionDate":"9/15/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All of the following food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American national standards institute, utilizing the conference for food protection standards:  (a) A food service establishment that is not any of the following:    (i) Operating under a temporary food service establishment license.  (ii) A vending machine location.     (b) An extended retail food establishment.  (c) Operated within a retail grocery.  (2) An individual certified under subsection (1) shall be recognized with full faith and credit by the state and all local units of government throughout the state.  (3) The department may promulgate rules to do all of the following:  (a) Develop requirements for retail food establishments to follow when employing certified food safety managers or personnel.  (b) Set a reasonable date for compliance with the requirements under subdivision (a) taking into consideration existing local personnel certification requirements.  (c) Establish certification fees necessary to implement, maintain, and track certified individuals directly or by contract. The department may annually adjust the schedule of fees to provide that the fee charged is sufficient to cover the cost of the certification tracking program.  (d) Implement and enforce the requirements described in subdivision (a).    (4) The certification program developed by the American national standards institute, as it exists on April 1, 2008 , is incorporated by reference. The department may adopt updates to the certification program accreditation standards in subsection (1) by rule.     (5) This section does not prohibit any local legislative body from implementing a food handler program, an employee health certification program, or a manager certification program, if it is not in conflict with this section.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Missing","subProblem":"","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide."}]},{"inspectionid":"38424","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","inspectionDate":"2017-03-09T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"128","pcount":"1","pfcount":"0","ccount":"2","criticalcount":"1","noncritical":"2","correctedcritical":"1","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"38424","inspectionDate":"3/9/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"3-501.18","violationDescription":"A FOOD specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A) or (B) shall be discarded if it:  \r\n    (1) Exceeds the temperature and time combination specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A),              except time that the product is frozen; (P)\r\n    (2) Is in a container or PACKAGE that does not bear a date or day; (P) or\r\n    (3) Is appropriately marked with a date or day that exceeds a temperature and              time combination as specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A). (P)  \r\n\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-09T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"inspectionid":"38424","inspectionDate":"3/9/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"6-301.14","violationDescription":"A sign or poster that notifies FOOD EMPLOYEES to wash their hands shall be provided at all HANDWASHING SINKS used by FOOD EMPLOYEES and shall be clearly visible to FOOD EMPLOYEES.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"BATHROOM","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-09T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"inspectionid":"38424","inspectionDate":"3/9/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All of the following food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American national standards institute, utilizing the conference for food protection standards:  (a) A food service establishment that is not any of the following:    (i) Operating under a temporary food service establishment license.  (ii) A vending machine location.     (b) An extended retail food establishment.  (c) Operated within a retail grocery.  (2) An individual certified under subsection (1) shall be recognized with full faith and credit by the state and all local units of government throughout the state.  (3) The department may promulgate rules to do all of the following:  (a) Develop requirements for retail food establishments to follow when employing certified food safety managers or personnel.  (b) Set a reasonable date for compliance with the requirements under subdivision (a) taking into consideration existing local personnel certification requirements.  (c) Establish certification fees necessary to implement, maintain, and track certified individuals directly or by contract. The department may annually adjust the schedule of fees to provide that the fee charged is sufficient to cover the cost of the certification tracking program.  (d) Implement and enforce the requirements described in subdivision (a).    (4) The certification program developed by the American national standards institute, as it exists on April 1, 2008 , is incorporated by reference. The department may adopt updates to the certification program accreditation standards in subsection (1) by rule.     (5) This section does not prohibit any local legislative body from implementing a food handler program, an employee health certification program, or a manager certification program, if it is not in conflict with this section.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"34535","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","inspectionDate":"2016-09-20T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"128","pcount":"0","pfcount":"0","ccount":"3","criticalcount":"0","noncritical":"3","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"34535","inspectionDate":"9/20/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"On top of the Upper shelf","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"inspectionid":"34535","inspectionDate":"9/20/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"ceiling","problemDescription":"Not clean","subProblem":"","location":"PASTA PREP ROOM","subLocation":"On the ceiling Ceiling vent cover(s)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean"},{"inspectionid":"34535","inspectionDate":"9/20/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1021","name":"Giovanni's Ristorante","violationCode":"3-304.12","violationDescription":"During pauses in FOOD preparation or dispensing, UTENSILS shall be stored:\r\n(A) In the FOOD with their handles above the top of the FOOD and the container;\r\n(B) In FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS with their handles above the      top of the FOOD within containers or EQUIPMENT that can be closed, such as      bins of sugar, flour, or cinnamon;\r\n(C) On a clean portion of the FOOD preparation table or cooking EQUIPMENT\r\n(D)  In running water, such as dipper well.\r\n(E)  In a clean, protected location if the UTENSILS, such as ice scoops, are   used only with a FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS; or\r\n(F)  In a container of water maintained at a temperature of at least 135° F.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Dispensing utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly stored","subProblem":"With handle in product","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Inside the Bulk food containers","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-02-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store with handle extended out of product."}]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"1021"}}